city yesterday i had it not
for the first of all soda proclaimed
creating a clock and directory
and then putting the or file on there
and hoping i think the max
i'm switching things up so that the or
files in the same directories were
working on
speed you use the controls the controls
the for gravel
to run
circling
you can
without having to worry about which
directory it said
scrambling at same place in life is
easier
if you look great here
make directory dash p filled with flash
pots slash
artisanal a stock it is possible
hopefully by now it's certain to become
a little bit familiar
seating around in making directories and
doing it every day
you know watch out for me
acacia review caroll hemlock farms
and my brain defaults w get
but i think if the trouble on that
walk away from it
lincoln park
uh... so yeah go if you have a show or
any you can view court of offers
ticklish
it's not gonna save it from last time
yet the crucial each time
so you can give control x two
i think everything
and then
you can also suspend your virtual
machine adjust come back to the next
time i'm suspended right
than do men xcel
that make sure that you've but the or
file in your class ten directory
so if you haven't done that
few very differently it somewhere else
remember you can't move files around
with the and buchanan's
and heat
annual eighteen and i had a right at the
whole all intents forgot or
fill that slot
class
sliced and
for ten
suffered some or else you can get that
file over to your class area
did you copy and paste the your or the
post typing it
you didn't you actually typed it animus
types the u_ r_ o_
so if you take a look at the class no
scroll down
steelers talent
click in their aunts go along with the
and you'll see that this codes you can
just copy and paste
because you were taking two genes and
with its cute
as opposed to you
so this is a q and a g_i_s_ in there and
you had g_g_
sociology tds
to be really careful way
letter keel and the letter g_
look kinda similar trio watch out for
this fall apart here where do you think
q g_i_s_ today
and that's a few energy
let's get started
but because they are on your homework a
little bit
by going through doing the same thing
you're doing
i'm gonna hide my firefox into just for
max
sore first entry
creating uh...
who work what entry emina go open up
why
logfile subtilis locked dropbox
walrus
research tools than
dash in my last name dot org
this is the law timekeeping in this
class
i_q_ december one time during this
mostly just so you guys see exactly the
same thing
referred back to notes here
from the start off by giving myself a
hint a minute include a file if you ever
need to bring texan from another file
its control act
and uh... on it
so i a prereq for notes here things to
do
so i propose up this information or that
i fall than what we're doing this
and here's how i make an entry
active gotten through this class if you
like this kind of styled note-taking you
can pick your own
style had already noted in the leg up
file pertaining to do
organize improper project it's totally
up to you
i'm gonna make a day
so in here who say september
twenty nine
and that's a calm today
cancer
familiar controls the period
put in the date
now if i did was wrong
thankfully today the computer is
agreeing with what it is
but i think that the other day if i
don't like the day site if it's lonely
without presenter
we now have a big step in there
i'm gonna add a tag
with control c
control c
secure all along you can create an entry
for yourself and your logfile insider
dropbox
and that's how you with a
and teaching
considered for me at all about teaching
only create entry with the stars as the
second level having
and i've talked
seattle
poll
so here i can say and the fact that with
gravity
and i was preparing and i was june
gardener for the day
all tied with his name
and so we talked about smith
saying lol
that's all that we have to be if you
want but you have to be anything special
but hero create one for research tools
research tools
q g_i_s_
and
shelved
and hopefully some might bite on
and if you work in a day if you know you
have something you need to deal you can
treat yourself some entries
so i've got a list here with some
injuries that you get checked off
create entry for geo sh
i want to show you exporting along so
you can see what it looks like so will
to uh... controls the control he
the latter b
you know c
if you drop boxes running you should see
as much as part of piano at least one of
you has dropbox not working
but at after you save your research
tools logfile since the dropbox it's
gonna sent over to them
at the crime scene and mac
lewis is coming through on my virtual
machine submarine dropbox both on the
first machine in the polls
ignore those
but in here you can see
here's my check boxes from before
and here are my interest for today
by myself with gravity and richard
gardner
and you can and go to these things since
they are
so that could be my entry for today
if you guys are working in the class new
you wanted notes like if you see
something in the arctic channel
and you hope we have all logged into the
ir c channel now
you'll actually have that
available to you afterwards
do that before i forget
annex university
analog unfair to channel
you can do it through chat so uh... or
there's notes on how to do with the
artsy
and that's a research
tools
so-called an h
image
research
so anyway that's the the set up for that
in different sectors are pretty good
you're it
and worry here it
the internal injury
put stuff in the directory cost and an
export
and so now we're on to you
go use q g_i_s_ so any anybody stock at
this point before we jump onto actually
side
it's nowhere
it's my it's my favorite
you can have my second i think i think
you're out bailout
it's hidden in my drop off if you don't
have permission to leave
that's boat candy
some of your export for growth
how do you make the html file before
so board exports
if you want to see it
wires
control
control of the
and then the letter to you for each team
our export
you can do whatever you want for your
interest with the tech it'll have really
is the notes for yourself
experts who have to figure out what's
going to work for that you can make a
checklist
or ukraine
not worry about you can read a paragraph
you know if you like
v isn't what this is the uh...
html
and open
in the web browser
but like a bird one-third lots of other
ones and some of them are
i'm not even sure what to do with some
of the sender
there's like an excel excel format or
something like that but i'm
i don't know about this
so if you need to get back to your notes
we've been doing awesome from the
keyboard
do with the purely a little bit here so
you can see them
ekits goes like live offers on the go
back to that working on file for today
this next century
for this class if you haven't done it
you need to go watch the four videos
that i created for you on utube
for about an hour and fifteen mins total
and there there so you can hit pause
and think about stuff you can go back
through it you can review later on this
master if you forget
it goes through creating work load files
exporting
and i'm guessing from now on that you
actually know how to do all the stuff in
there
i'm gonna keep moving unless someone
stops me on a particular topic
in general i'm in assuming you know how
to
get around the max a little bit if you
had trouble let me know
but in general and assume that you got
it
time to get going on the python stuff
and spend less time money max because i
think height on it
more fun long-run that he max alike the
max but
i don't want to get our job done
so let's go
you sunday night
and last time we get google earth in it
was grumpy
so i'll show you a tool that isn't quite
so far beyond the virtual machine
let's go
if you've already got
the files from last time
we built the camel of boston the
construction and we have an ex-wife i'll
if i'm over here in terminal
i'm in class and so if you do p dignity
i mean research tools box and then ten
if i do know us dot dot slash zero nine
if you see
that's co cup and compressed be
considered
start
easy to you
i'm gonna go ahead none compressors cuz
for some reason i compress them
so if you know let's talk dot slash zero
nine
that looks up one directory is dot dot
so that's the parent directory there's
going to look and class nine we had last
time
so i i want a copy over
c_p_ dot gov slash
ceremony
two thousand seven being tab for
completion
and a copy of the came out
animal have put it in the current
directory which is dot
eliminate the apparel
dissipating wanted ex-wife
so in your directory
you should now have your
or will file for a lecture today
fostering construction came out and
that's why i think if you don't have
them
on your desk
if you had trouble with the last lecture
read to him
which i did a myself last week
you can use it at the equinox put them
up
on the server so you can just pull them
back down if you can't find
computer
uh... yeah
dot that's why i a m came out at the top
of that
yet doing our special
uh... do another one
it's all confusing when iraq's cecily
unit good insists when the terminal blue
short it wrapped around other i have the
same thing where racks of courtesy
so you get a cpa there was an error here
sing-sing in the vicinity of the
sub-acute care today austrians
states and period
so you need it but the copy about the
destination
to enter
and happy during our stock show you'll
see the first one reading through the
same thing for the ex-wife file
in
so you know
if you look at the following you've got
a couple extra curricular
here
dua control expert roll-up
hoops control g
businesses you know
faculty
immediately drop box
uh...
we picked up again
it's got a couple days yep so read
i think he didn't press center
and there it is
you open up a different offer that was
very similar names
tonight anyway feet
did you stay here or file into the right
place at the u_n_ right one
critical to the people who put certified
continued open the file
actually are working toward violence in
their top-level directory completely
control expert public statement collects
we're gonna kill black cyclical wade
it's and political business controllers
dollhouse idealistic class town
kellogg
tonight opened it contributed forty four
pieces that were actually in that
directory if you seem to work on the
wrong place individuals he controls the
instead of working electorate left of
interest
so now he's going to make guardian
search for
particularly cute images from that
should work
but have control c control seal on that
january happens the place is called a
little bit more frightening
appear your
this what will your going way fast
it's better to
put the mouse away
ignore the mouse
so i'm not sure which one return before
right
if you're perfect if you do here and you
know once you have everything you need
sears your radio maxed out
ls
and that is that the affair
let's start to g_i_s_
so you can run this from other ways but
the easiest ways applications science
halloween star one finds application so
far
who hadn't unki g_i_s_
so that what they shouldn't
science
and once you're in q g hats
if you have read parked yes the system
more but allot simpler
doesn't have quite so many features
running around
which often can be a benefit because
so we're gonna go under layers
and you're not add of doctor lawyer we
have that came out from before
in q ta s
he doesn't know how display every kind
of came out
but nothing else has clear lines
so go ahead and get abductor layer
dropping at the browse button
cruising around and finding out
and if you remember we've been working
in our clocks directory
with that
today's lecture time
and nothing shows up it kinda looks
depressing
uh... if you look down here on the
bottom right
there is a menu of file types
these are all different file types that
he she adds this person is not open
uh... if you worked with marine charts
before you might remember
at fifty seven so if you have a nasty
seven-term it'll open it right up my
don't know what it will do good
hope we'll see some of the chart
we're gonna pick came out
so pick came out
and you should see
two thousand seven boston construction
camo
click opened
and winery
selected
and a quick open
personal clinic and because the first
open wasn't enough
if you guys when it really hard
there is a
fairy pink blue line on the projector it
is impossible see that should show
better on your
screens the projector is a very good at
color
does everybody have
lines on your screen
now you have to do interpret this like a
plot testing tell me do you see like a
chicken doing the dance floor
so if you have data values formats and
you just want to see what's in that file
q g_i_s_ is your friends are put up and
see if you can open it since you got
will use this a whole bunch throughout
the rest the semester will learn a lot
more about it
but i want you to a cd g_i_s_ once
missing data
and will season tickets at smu season
again again in different ways to look at
them
every century huge e_a_s_ we haven't
done anything very interesting with it
but you seem to get will go ahead and
killed hugh g_i_s_
some of the way
close without saving
this is a whole zero dollars
i have what it what it comes down to his
accounts on people like us to contribute
back to me and if you're not a program
and you can contribute with
documentation
or examples
telling people about it
teaching your friends about it
so we've now gone through the q gaf
section
and bring it into a
our last topic with
michelle sort of your bash from now on
after today batches just there in the
background to help us move files around
amber and not worry about too much
we're going to focus on pipe on a this
but i want to see example rebuild
a movie so we're actually going to go
make
and to do that we need to learn a little
bit about bash variables there not
is easy to follow as piperlime they've
got some courts
clements pope my screen on the show you
a couple examples thriller just enough
to deal with old script today
and if you get into this in you are more
and more
we can point you in a number of good
books
and people talk to you
bullets go
creation also pneumatic x shell
give myself a terminal here so i don't
have to keep jumping around
and we'll try some variables here just
to see
to warn you
this class a lot of it is about
precision
it's being careful type exactly what you
need to type
and we're doing the examples if you
start typing random things back soon
if you get a little crazy
if i screw up
it's going to get sickness marriage the
first thing rages creative variable
so if i do testing
equals
twenty three
i had not done when i type before and it
might not work
instead of working it says i don't know
this command testing that you want
monica ron
so we have to make sure we type of
exactly so down here
you can't with spaces around those equal
signs and bash it's very picky about
that
sofas a testing
equals one two three
that's actually create a variable called
testing except the value to be the
string
one two three
now in python you won't see the dollar
sign
we had echo shelved
last class so we just tried something
out that this show that you're running
if he's a dollar signs the special
variables we can go look at our variable
dollar testing
and it prints out one two three
so if i say testing equals
echo
dollar testing
so now i said to hello world
so that's a creative variable and
michelle
definitely touchy
it also has a problem and that if we
create
every one of the program and it needs to
know that verbal it's going to lose it
so if we create the second shell
we're gonna run bash
and we're now on a new shell
family side echo dollar testing
there's no testing variable it's gone
so if you try to run things inside of
another script and you said a variable
it's not going to know about it
papers that he left picky about that
they'll keep track of things better for
us
if your father what's going on
so could you exit
believe that one show
so
its effect remember her do that
in color
so there's a variable called shell level
s_h_
alvie how
this is pretty advanced stuff
if you can write that down and if you
use it will be very proud of you
how i think that he's a couple times in
my life
and every type bash again and we've had
echo dollar shell model
opacity
well confusing
just to give you a little flavor of
what's going on
the churches
if we want that variable to stick around
and he used elsewhere
we're gonna have to say
export
testing equals twenty three
and that keeps that very ball around so
the any
program the kids call with that
and the case for this comes into to
become important is it
we typed echo dollar editor
there's no other if you want to tell
the system that you have
preference that you liked you max
you can say
export
editor equals
he max
and now what it wants in
to have a tax ever for u_s_ can use the
max rather than the eye
it's going to fall to the allied
and you're gonna get weird interface
you've never seen before and very
frustrated
delivery has its weird export mechanism
gets very complicated
and when we got a pipeline
you're not worry about it being like
that so this is my
advertising for quite on overshot
but let's go ahead
we've done our export testing up here
we're going now
tie backs again jump in the second cell
for now and this new shelf space
and if we tried to go
dollar testing
we still have our variable
so when you see export
that means that it's gonna stick around
for any trial process if you're if you
were a program for men they rebelled now
about your variable
if you fall of of the videos
and you start looking at setting up
sooner parameters if you actually needed
at your basher see down the road between
the need to do
door about right now but will probably
come back if you see again so wanted
with her at once suicide attempt verdict
maybe it'll stick a little bit better
will be setting things like your at
your editor equals the mexican set up
your printer this way
default printer in the building things
like that
it's not so that much fun
but it's important to know
was released on a little
so if you call anything from this once
you set it he stays in nashville will
fall and other programs that will go to
everywhere on the computer
that what you're asking
yet is if you look at the video there's
a coconut
the online videos if you do you
last till slash doc dash r_c_
this is your setup file
for the show
so go ahead to enter
to a signals and brake
and turn signals in the killing
how would you control excommunicate
and center
killed up offered
and then open up a new job
it was confused
sidhu amanda x
which are not being fully functional
means inside of you max
dot the program there can't control the
display as much as they would like to
sofian over here
in a real terminal
we did last total slash
top bachelor sea
kinda like a man paid reconstruct roll
back and forth and
mercury
this one
it gently kind of unhappy
you're back first e-file will see down
the road a few times
contains all of your settings
so control lacks control f
till two slash
dot basher received
agonist whole lot of fancy shell
scripting
and down the road your you learn bits
and pieces of it as you go
but if it is in pretty fancy things in
here
and i don't actually follow all of them
are pretty advanced
so in this is what controls your entire
system
and in windows even set up like a
requirement for the control panel
this is way more powerful than that
and without power the power company
competition but
anyone q_v_c_'s
now and they were not gonna worry about
it until reaction to come back in
accurate with vista
you do see a couple times and then try
to use a few times and you'll start to
get the hang of it
so let's go back
if you get out of it you can't have a q
from your last or if you want to kill
your shell you can do a control acts
just kill a dead
press enter
type yes to kill it
as gone it's degrade restart
so let's go down here and we read
you might have told we had a good
feeling for variables and bash
when you work your python you'll see
variables when you go back to bash later
on and you will start to get the hang of
it
let's create a scripts
i think that's going to be fun because
it had a lot i mean to us as a group
put onto the creating a script section
i see a baseball
you going to control al
bigger screen gets all confused it means
it is having trouble redrawing extreme
correctly
uh... so quick on like firefox down here
on the left
and then put back in the maximum should
book
it had trouble you're on the screen for
some reason
i don't know why through nafta
control l redrawn since understates
so you can do you have control expo
to jump to the mini bar from
blacks in the middle
you know controlled g book without a
doubt
and active
you're you everything
so you can you tell that offer
control x
communicate and press enter
yes
do you have two different max is going
uh... killed one of them
milling in one twenty max of the time
yes over
i do it
you want to the same file twice
do control x one
and then control xti
if you click on this link and your
screen doesn't freak out on you
and click on mozilla firefox
we are going to cause lamont doherty
webserver to freak out
just like we did with uh... the irish
thichai
any near is a very boring looking to
record that is actually really cool
this is the camera
on the top of the ship
and every hour a new picture gets sent
back by satellite
for wal-mart webserver
and you can see the latest picture
from an icebreaker run by the u_s_ coast
guard
so if you click on a random picture
and stop and all the light box a dozen
overnight
so here is the mill that i can dot
harbor alaska
so this lets you see out of the world
into a moving platforms
hopefully down the road more ships will
let us do this
aunties and then you can see what's
going on the docks in dutch harbor
so what would like to do today
is to make a movie because this is a
time series every how ur
what they call a movie see what it's
like driving on the ship
and i've done this word action taken a
whole summer for the pictures
and turn them into a movie you can watch
the hwy drive from seattle
up to the arctic and back
a lot of fun you can watch a ship
sitting at the pier and watch what i do
a pin down
pretty crazy
so let's make a movie of those
and to do that we read download one
day's worth of images
but rather then click on each one and
save them
because that's no fun especially if you
want download several hundred
we're gonna go crazy if we do that
we're going to create a script that does
it for us
and we'll do it all out some for band
it would and it was scaled to doing many
days a week said
pictures old ones
so let's go ahead and create a file that
search shell scripts
so what you can do is if you name it
keeley dot bash in your directory
and you can
click this link it should take you to
some of it doesn't exist
so enough file called keeley dot bash or
he can do a control x control f
and not file
and that was not going system so we save
it to discuss something in there
judy
him and u
that's a great question
too lazy that one is control c control
al the setup bowling but i can also
switched the text on
when you met xd xd
and it's going to get like
woodwork bodega
does all the formatting hot stuff
so there's two square brackets file call
until two slash
hwy dot bash
bother happen there
going to go back
uh... there's a lot of fancy things in
in orbit what you do stuff like that and
that's why i think it makes a great
note-taking
tool for
scripting and we're not because you can
link to files all over your computer
as you figure stuff out you can point to
it you can open up configuration files
that uh...
so we're going to learn how to do a
poorly
in the shelf
summer it was over a bunch of stuff
so a four loop
here it is different between fashion
python
whereas a four
and you're going to put your very well
got four our
to this case that's going to be our
thread you one picture every hour
and then you're going to have a list of
things you want to have here
so we're going to the first hour zero
one since they count with
zeros in there
and is going to go all the way they
sleep twenty three
and so that's going to be sent through
this link
it's going to put it
a number watches a string of looks like
a number into this variable called a
hour
and then you'll be able to use that to
create the right
command-line to go out and grab our file
off the web
i think a new used if you get that for
getting together alan's case
do
is the beginning of what you're going to
run for each flu
and then you stayed on at the end
and then in here
you get to do stopping time around
with this variable hours set to be your
number
so if you actually want to processing on
that you can actually do a bunch of
stuff but
for in our case for a loop through
twenty times paragraph each hour
so it's stalked by copying
this section in here
before our in
anand easier wanted to do i kept a
southerner some number like that make
sure you get the zero
before each number
pilot a region do matted
w for copy
grover here
weather control y
yet you'll notice a change their colors
in here
this knows it's a shell scripts an suv
type batch
so it knows about variables and for
loops and as for the keyword
this is where it might very first party
in this country was working on it
i ran over to the shelved
the hearing in the class
and there's no cuba dot batch
wait a second request for payroll
we have to go back over here and you
have to say this
faces of stars dot i remember that
there's
their stars and and and saved if you've
never stated at all
doesn't exist on the desk so control x
control s
and you can see it now wrote the file
into our path
to go back over here
ls dash l
there is now a healy dot bash script
so let's give it a shot and see if we
can write inflicted first have to see if
we're on the right track
we're gonna run that by brinkman called
source
and then hwy
glenview enter our lives up here but you
may answer
and see if you get a whole bunch of
numbers on your screen
should say zero three seven one proline
as you go through
so she wanted to check book like that
so you're in that features so
when yeah
tonight in dallas that show
and they have the script syntex source
states do you think about that
all you have in there that palin file is
the auto saved file
of about thirty minutes
gupta buffers
and find that he wabash spilled onto it
senior in the forefront alice's he's up
hits like that
needed pasting the text in there
you know edit copy
taste
and save
control its control us soon
now go to the following an
rerun your listing
press center
and i didn't know you can transport it
so what this is doing
take a quick because this is doing
therefore
hours so how r is going to be our
variables getting upset at half staff in
each time through
every time there's a space in between
here is that take one of those little
bits of string and pasand through
arrangement
and we have a very exciting to me in
here that
echoes out to the consul
which is gonna print out
whatever that variable is
over-covered here
its printing out zero one zero two zero
three zero four so do the hours of the
day we can use those
in a command to build up the string and
want to get back because the
we're looking for a day
though i think changing the file name
for the days the hour
so let's take a look through our
examples here
we're gonna use curl to go grab out
what we're gonna do is we're gonna add
redhat this curl
soviet control space
all the way up to
the minus sign over there
but here's copper the whole thing
uh... w
anomaly coherence item in the week this
dollar-an-hour
and the paste
with a control y
exchanged at the our
because if i wrote
in here
echo
taller
our
zero
i now have a new variable called our
zero one
and it's not going to work
so in back she can put curly braces
funny curly braces of america round a
variable name and then it will
separate out the stuff
from the stuff
and give this woman tries this but make
sure that you save it before you try it
self control x
control s
the trip says wrote the file down below
here at the bottom
and rear on that
and hopefully
you can see something like that picture
you're not you didn't save orient i
think what we're looking for
done because the previous control c
yesteryear on his back row inside
right where the door powers
so now
ben question yes
lives
he's worst
uh... is
lines
because i was gonna
go back through the after i get the
source
so now
to run the script and do the whole thing
let's at all the hours
zero eight three twenty three six type
of stocks you can
though making mistakes
you can
it's just gets really complicated with
bash nazi josephine i thought he
receives a lot simpler and by phone
yes this is just uh... like let's have
fun with the reflect
it's really powerful and that
i wrote a ten thousand line bashed shell
script set
that controlled
a spacecraft processing chain to get all
the image processing for us
out more space craft
and then someone took my coat and wrote
a hundred thousand wine version of that
for fearing opportunity it still running
every day
actually runs every couple minutes
it's but it's a hundred thousand want to
stop that
very few of us can even figure out
what's going on
it gets a whole lot
difficult or quit
was something
what
weaker than by phone
well he didn't quite know hope
that i was a better way to go we felt
that that should be simple and then
it was simple for the first time lines
so let me say this
and remove the ako
the eco was just telling us what it what
what is wanting to do
now for a move that echo
echoes a great weight sa description and
try to do it support of before you run
the whole thing
but once they revert back with actually
gonna go and get all those files
and will see if the system
administrators at lemont
cost up because they know us and say why
in the world and you guys doing
so go ahead and source that and want to
attack their web server
it's going to go hopefully you're gonna
see a whole lot of curl outputs of the
downloads all those files
as he was to couples friends going
we'll see if we can make it go really
slow
and if you do you
so that the command on the bottom again
source hwy dot
so now you should see something like
that your directory listing a whole pile
of stuff
yet delia carley also show that they
could be confused guy
off the files
take a look at your script
the demons did you remove your echo
calling it it just print but not to run
the command
who the echo
now save it
and now you're on your script
will see if we get blocked by their
network admin
street zeroed out
them
that's a great question do we exclude
the zero zero so please take a look at
okay so to look at their
directory
the way they've run they have what's
called a cron job that runs every hour
on the computer
and packet that script right just after
the hour in the next minute
so can actually save the file name with
zero one on there
and so we're following what they did
soaked at the first minute of every our
there right
the file name
as zero one
so we have to follow
what files they put up on the web
that i've read out
they have a zero zero in the pile up
that out you can either
your you're more of our combat it
this is you know this is sort of
distressing around the try things out
and see what you get
that's a great question because i shows
for how programming works and you try
something out and say wow ok it worked
for me given to someone else they're
like
why did you do that it doesn't make any
sense unocal yeah that was dumb
and then you fix it go on
so we have a whole bunch of files
if i make this go way out of control x
zero i want to script anymore
see more of its
we've done
ramesh preps
i bet you image magic
and this program converts
images from very for much of a risk for
matt's it's actually extremely powerful
it looks pretty boring when we start
but it can make movies and do all kinds
of other things
so i have to actually get britain out
here and i have to look this up in my
notes
it knows how to make it was called
animated gif and if any of you browse
the web in the nineties he profits all
one of these like
silly flashing images and i can't really
annoying
eaten converts
he stayed away
one hundred this is the number of
milliseconds between each frame that's
going to show
loop zero
if you could tell me if i was gonna win
through before quits
zero means
never quit
poor and give it all of our
images
so star dot j peds
means takes all of our j pig images
and we're gonna write it to and you can
pick a simpler filing hit or type it
i'm right up to g_i_ effort gift for a
chip
everyone said
and this is going to make an animated
sequence of
images in one file the commode up in
firefox
so may go ahead of copy this line so
malad w
list you've made an excel
difficult myself
animated do control why the pace that in
there
enter
and it's gonna sit there and look like
it's broken
but don't budget
let it go
toothpaste in that command and give it a
run
that comes back so it takes a good few
seconds for to run through a builder
stuff
if we take a look with a lot that self
serve our guests
there is now jeff
there's now a very large
file americans are animated movie
if it is running firefox angier
disagreements and and lazy
replaced in the file commands
it's gonna tell us that we have
i'd get rid of them too much about it in
this program but at least its
if we also do you
identifying might get something a little
bit more
and identify dearest vibe junk
school confused
but better yet lets just go look at it
so you can tell firefox to open it up
firefox
okays give the procure euro
leave open a buffer with some other
names
so that's not a show
that's just a land fall
so if you are not x show
so now you're intermittently concerned
supercenter
and i had to wait about ten or fifteen
seconds
uh... all that jonathan
identifying which are shouldn't have
shown because it just give you
gross output or identify
if you don't hear methods that separate
and uh...
that's a great one um...
if you get weird message about knowledge
a bag
i'll show you the command to run to see
what's going on
right this is a great time he's filed
star dot jpg
and hopefully it should say
everything is
uh...
the word used a lawyer and anyone women
script
sinead internally that
acadia peter the evening
tell us that show
them for the year shell
inside there
few api dvd
national defense
ls sellers
interest
and o_j_ p_g_ allen-mia daria
yet make sure you have the entire this
is
this is a great illustration have
extensions
some people call a jpg in some college
a_p_ e_g_
and so if you get used to one
though three for a link
c
you're adding have explained to the
order
so if you look back here
you're seeing out the window of the
healing
i do agree
right
helpful
well behind you actually ahead
graders in the past us
d they also of the last one
there's something wrong with alan i
would just are in that file
and
jerry engineering involved
you know i'm just
you know you needed to just armando
on
the dash in their tab of your friend
whom to complain stuff
and his arm that
enter running now
the convert community because
okay we've got people are doing a movie
who are ahead
i couldn't explain the idea is
darryl ahead welfare
so if we were in firefox
and i think it's going to you
filled the creator although
ignore that that something from inside a
fire fox worries grumpy about something
it doesn't matter
a lot of times these programs have
internal bugging messages
and there's probably something that's
meant not for us basement for somebody
who actually
develops firefox and then left in there
by accident
and you can see that we have an animated
movie
looking out the front of a healing
and it's actually working so ignore that
trouble
so do control space
control a
in fact the laundromat at that meeting
and and the other one
and control y
again context
knapper center
an angry skype tonight and see how the
front of the hwy
you can pick you degrade you could
change that you are out to be some of
the day he might pick something whether
in the ice is breaking ranks
this is how we know that
larry maher just got off the ship
yesterday
whether he wants us to know or not
we can see the people then actually i
knew because someone else on the shirt
and they'll say
for getting off the ship
that's why i picked yesterday
uh... before another example bogdan
breaking on easter something from last
year were sitting in a charmer
for this shows you
uh... they change their camera so we can
all see it night which is a lot better
but that's create a little movie insists
the power shell scripting we could go in
there and we could set up a ranger with
the second for with the pic days and we
could maybe pick their an entire month
and you can make a giant movies a month
the file size of the immediate isn't
very good it's going to take fast
but you're on the road towards
being able to put together movies and
create whatever you need you for your
projects
for now on
we're gonna try and get docs as much as
possible because it's
sort of annoying
emory allot of python
so hopefully if i've done this right my
lecture notes a now we're gonna go to
fight them
let one last thing i'm gonna show you
which is what ben brought up in a
almost forgot it
and this is why we have notes
so you's guys saw that
we had to run the source command so we
did source don't run again because you
know this free download a bunch of junk
out we had the source
if you look here on the left
he says
r_w_ for read write
nana read and read meaning that we can
read break the file
anybody else in the computer can read
the file
it's missing executed lol
the way you said something executed will
use a c_h_ mine
plus tax
healy dot bash
that's been said
this bios executed by anybody
and if we re run our
tell us that cell
you'll now see a bunch of axes appears
so extremes execute a bull
not sure it's going to work i think it
in fact will fail
brooke looked back
don't we run it but
and
the better way to do this to protect
yourself to make sure that it actually
runs the right show because there are
different
types of shells and other people don't
use bash necessarily
what you would do is america back to the
hwy shell scripts
if you put the first wine and
if we copy this
it looks weird
the reason this is it's just because
someone chose it
it hasn't funky properties that that
work for them
we're gonna see this also a pipe bombs
camilla different for python
this first line of a text file if you
say
a pound
on the number sign
bang for the estimation mark
and then
slash bin slash bash whatever doctor
this is the program is run
and then given the text for this file
so this later on will cvs
i thought in there
and watch as they go on this
file of python code
if you have the same hearing you saved
it
then this means that if someone's using
a different shell
it will go
startup bash for them
one that script and at the annual quite
out of that bash still take everything
for them
and you'll see is a democrat on
so when you guys to see that a little
bit before we went on but you can always
just from source
and it will ban execute the stuff inside
of a file within that shelf
so it's pretty simple
elixir
we're going to be using a shell that's a
little bit more advanced than the
regular pipeline shelled we're going to
use i've pipeline
hyper indigo
they're doing
some newer versions out there
zero point one morning zero point one
two
if you read the documentation for those
there's more features
and they'll get in the way you try
things that don't work
so we're going to utica zero point ten
point to you
except with a link in here for the
application that if you want to read
more
read this version don't read the newer
ones
we're gonna try and find some release
ny teachers that don't exist
yet in our version
is getting some really fancy features
for
basically
billing documents and showing figures
inside michelle
waiver and always run it
like this were always gonna give it dash
p y al abt
this is going to set us up for work our
way trade u
and graphing and run all the signs tools
so what's copy back
sumana w
and go over the terminal really candace
type this if you want to know and then
you can always had cleared at title that
junk
attitude control c control see that's
meant to go up to run something that
finishes
and i python isn't going to finish
we can set up
i fight on to ron in a little cecil
window kind of like frenetic shell
but that requires more setup steps i
haven't tested them yet
you guys have done so much setup
that because not fair to make you give
any more setup for a couple days
so go ahead type clear
and then i python
dash by lab
the first time you were an ipod found
it's gonna look different than every
other time because candies and set up
policy if it happens here
presenter
this setup
your lawyer see it break now and the
first time
anneke switch machines you'll see it
again
deficit in half
configuration files for ipod iphone
it really get it
funny prompt down here
in green
and i apologize if
for those of you guys who are colorblind
there's lots of reading green and more
people seem parts i apologize
you'll see this in
one risking run command one
and i wanted you one thing before we go
anywhere else and that's how to get out
exit
and to print the scenes
if you just type exit
it's very tell you
i didn't like that i knew what you meant
but i'm not going to do it
please type of parentheses
parentheses and now
because they do you really want to do
that
and decompress enter or wine
and now you're out
i don't know
many ways to exit you can do some other
funny things in a probably cause of the
quick too
at capitol records are we might have
some special meaning
and we have to look it up
please type exit and
but pretty great friend
fearing that setup partridge says
depressed returned to start pythons so
press wells thinkcentre
and exit
and needed to go
it's nothing like being stuck in a
programming
not knowing how to kill it happened just
killed the child
so what's
restarted and it's gonna look different
this time it's not going to go through
that setup phase
so now
if you look silly here
it started up with al going through that
will set up a
from a controlled my notes up a little
bit here
and you'll see i think the animals
samples the into that again
tearing it up
learning how to be exit
and we're back into it
i fight on
brings with it a little bit of trash
it's copied some of the functionality so
we can do a p w d
norrell python doesn't have this command
we can do an ls
and wealthier directory
and as a whole bunch of commands like
that that we can do
and we'll be using more of those down
the road
you can do is c_b_ ductile
pvd
narrative for directory in ought to go
back
into you
b_n_l_ ask you see that i'm now one
level up
i can see back into
the cluster three times
known type of doesn't want to do that
and sometimes if you want to move
somewhere else and go work with some
files that are different area
they can get very frustrating
bullets go have some fun
i fight on its all set up reporting for
us with that command dash highland
we have our boston ex-wife borrow
if i do know by
load taxed
if you're used to matlab with the same
thing as well
type that
obvious ekkada catch-up and then we're
gonna pressed have and i'm in a cross my
fingers and hope they actually figures
out
they want
that i want to complete the file name
if you press tab
it will then complete out
as far as you can on the file name
there's also some irregular python
doesn't have
so if you're trying out some process
things that great way to
explore files and have that same tab
functionality we have before
so rich rambo tarek swine
go ahead and answer
and then it should tell you that because
of my quick it's got
do you follow along my cd and
i got ahead of you so do not control you
unique one no p_d_
seen here in class and go back into
tends to see these days
saturday ken anti five works for you
so his num five dot low-tax left
parentheses single quote
so if you look up here if you didn't get
an error and it worked
where actually want is tight was
this command right here
so this should give you an air
because we have a common till the matter
in our file and they didn't talented
comment on it
it will be wants space on it
since
we know we have
comment on the day that we can say
delimiter
and don't worry about trying to
understand how i knew all this just yet
will go through it and
were at every documentation for these
functions and figure them out
so we can say we note the delimiter is
and it's going to go up a lot of the
data into an array
but we really don't want that either
to give it a go and see if you get this
to work
etiquette six for all the keyboard so
you get your message synagogue run that
command at that
apparel
an advocate on their part
in this command you guys are adding
this text right here
and reviewed the uparrow to get the last
command
and and it so if i have apparel
downarrow
it also has the history commands
detectives during and you'll see your
history
and i'll keep showing you more commands
but there's lots and lots of nice things
like that and try to bar all the nice
parts of bash and leave behind across
the un fund parts
once you've got back
with such hope seeking to periods in
there
kick
yeah but you probably think dot that's
why he did not
and you had life
they had
a case of the last one of the show you
guys is that
if we stay on track
equals true it's going to split each of
the columns on this file into different
variables
and we can stay at scum ally equals
non-pilot tax
blah blah blah
and this is going to put the first call
an axe to second column in the wild
press enter
we now know what our data into t_v_
rebels
if we do
wife uh... x for example
a hundred almost martin twenty thousand
points in there
and the last commander today
is
this plot command to really go ahead and
plot guardia
flip-flopped
x com y
press enter
and this looks even more like a little
odd
in quite fast
and there's actually a some pretty cool
data if you know what it is
it's actually that ship working on and
undersea
national gas pipeline awful foster
and you can actually pick out if you
know what they were doing
shiite due to the port where the ship
stopped at the end the day
they're they're going out to work
this is where the terminal s
this is where the pipeline starts and
you could see them work along a pipeline
for many months
for these guys excavated
the bottom
put a pipe in their invented filled over
it once a dot
well it all together and this is
actually construction project in the
ocean and we can actually see all of
that today that was broadcast by the
ship
amorous start going thru and getting
more comfortable with being able to
discuss staffing for part a death
export to q g_i_s_ a back-and-forth
cfu g has actually knows pipeline so you
can see program q g_i_s_ from fight on
you can also program are g_i_s_ right on
at that hostile almost every spring
that's it for today guys